sword there wouldn't be a way to tell what event the photo is from right or is it if you click on
like the the photo like if you click on the details then i'll tell you
detail meaning the description yeah yeah
uh yeah i mean with with the tags of course we can tag everything we want so if you want we could
also create like an event tag and then have like multiple sub tags for that um it's completely up
to you guys the tag system is pretty like loose in that way so if you want to type by event we can
type by event um it already has a photographer in like built-in system so you can press search by
photographer too so it's it's just really um up to what we wanted to do although now i just came up
with the mvp 2024 because it's just like a description for it right otherwise it just becomes a generic
like outdoor bible but yeah i see what you guys are saying in that yeah like we might not need
to know it's from the mvp 2024 source right and then we can just put that in the description or whatever
yeah
yeah i um yeah so i was thinking like if we if we want to approach the naming from that
that the premise that we want to have only what is minimally necessary um whether that's the approach
we want um yeah if that's the case i i would say for sure the date i think that's very helpful
um and then also some kind of a identifier right like bible outdoor like those identifiers i think are
very helpful um i mentioned the date because i know that sometimes when people look at photos they
might be like oh this is outdated and then they just kind of have a way to verify very quickly oh this
photo is from like 20 years ago um yeah we might want to have more photos in these kind of um
game right but then yeah more more recent photos so yeah that's why i was thinking like if there's a
very quick way just from the date and mentioned in the file you can tell this is a really old photo or
this is like not that old yeah yeah for sure and then uh resource space also has a feature where you
can actually like archive some items so if you're going through and you're like oh you know this item
is like really old we don't want people using this we can just like park it archive it so it'll be there
for like historical like viewing purposes but you probably will not be able to like do anything
uh you probably won't be able to download it sorry yeah so that's a feature for resource space too
yeah in the in the data itself for each of the photo is there a place where we enter some kind of a date
info for the photo um i don't have resource based pull up right now so uh we can check when holly does
his presentation but i think there should be a date attached along with the location unless i'm
remembering wrong holly um so when so the way i get all the photos is i download them from lm the photos
directly so i don't really get to get all the details because if i want to get all the details like directly
if like everyone put on uh uh m photos we need like we need verification from the dk to like get all the
details from that so what we get is like no dates or something so what we can verify just
if they have like 2024 mvp or this folder name is like 2012 we can put them but we don't have like access to that
okay um yeah i i i i'm not sure if we have to have the date info for each of the photos i was just wondering if
there's something something like that especially if it's going to be part of the file name already i
think it's less even less of a concern for me um i was just curious and the other thing is like let's
say if we do want to put a date um for at least the most recent batches i don't know how easy it is to go
back to the other photos and get that info um but let's say if we want it from from all the mvps because the
mvps are already grouped by year right and we can just pick the last date of that mvp right as the
quote-unquote date for that particular batch of photos yeah yeah
sorry i'm not sure uh can you guys see this this screen right here the resource space with my dog
yeah yeah so there's uh yeah there's a date section the metadata is automatically pulled
uh okay yeah i see so because the photos in in the google photos i think there is a date right um
okay yes there should be um you can see the metadata and then when i pull them in from the
albums it puts them in so i tried doing it with the 1999 like sunflower photo it shows up as 1999 in my
own photos oh okay okay yeah so the metadata should automatically be attached i believe okay yeah it's
just i think sometimes when people take their photo using whatever camera um or phone where the date is
not set correctly then that's where maybe there could be some weird date data coming through right
yeah um so maybe that's just something we can um note down that in the guidelines that like in general
just make sure that they reflect um like correctly right um yeah so that at least it's it's in the note
it's in the guidelines um yeah so we don't get like you know how sometimes people's camera is set to like
50 years ago it's like you get these photos that's like 1972 or whatever whatnot it's just kind of odd
i i was just thinking it would be good to clean up those kind of info as part of the process right
of creating these in the art in the in the system yeah yeah for sure yeah so you can see for example
like this one is from one of the mvp 2024 photos right so it has like a correct date of roughly when mvp
would happen and you can see all this other like metadata of like what cameras used to take a photo
and then um yeah i don't know who else would have a chinese camera besides kelly but oh right yeah okay
yeah like this one's i i don't know what this photo was taken so i don't know this is the correct uh
date tag but i can but these these ones are correct for sure okay okay yeah maybe maybe we don't need to
spend the effort to go and make sure if those are correct it's just the the one that is very like
obviously like um you know from 50 years ago we just need to maybe we redate those but like the recent
ones you know if they're off by like months or whatnot you don't need to go back because it's possible i
think during mvp some people may actually upload photos that they took months ago uh because it's a good photo
um they they still uploaded it it was even though it was not something they did you know as part of
the field trip or during the mvp so that's that's fine as well we can just keep the original date for
those right there's no need to read those yeah yeah that's all fine like i think in the grand scheme
of things we can like of course discuss this as we get closer and closer like if this becomes a real
thing uh we can discuss this holly and i would just kind of come in with like an initial plan and then
yeah we can just see how it goes from there it's not a huge deal honestly sounds good yeah because
like it's just a file name right i think the resource space is a little more important since
this is how you actually search for stuff the file name is not like the most important thing
to us okay i see i see file name is more like just the actual file names that show up in wherever we
store them practices in the system yeah so like in the google drive or whatever if the backup it will
it will just show up as this name but it won't be like the most important thing because the name
will be here right but if you want to search for lunar you can just search up like the tags and stuff
and then yeah but yeah so it's just something we're more open to like discussing as we get closer too
yeah for sure um sorry any more questions on uh i guess the the naming scheme uh not before i go into
detail yeah okay okay yeah so um yeah as mentioned previously uh yeah subject's not really that important
we can of course figure out later um however holly and i did also come up with this thingy so it's like
the end here um it's kind of like the version um of the photo right there's because um i know there's
like multiple different stuff so for example like canva or canva also has to use the photos and then
because of it's for instagram we might have to like crop it right so you would have like two versions
um of the photo right like the original photo of whatever it is and then uh like a social specific
versions like an instagram specific version right to fit the whatever the photo like size needs to be
or maybe you want to put it onto the tjci website then you might have to do some more stuff with it
right like stretch it shrink it something like that so holly and i felt that we should add this kind of
descriptor to the end of it and then that way we can also restrict who can download it right so you
can't download the original but you can download the derivatives if you ever need to use the
derivatives for whatever reason basically yeah um yeah any question on that part that sounds good
okay yeah um holly is there anything you want to add to this section before i go on to the research part
uh no no no okay sounds good um yeah so another thing we had to do um was to research kind of the
integrations um or not integrations just like the other um stuff to do with the with resource space
right um there were some questions and then i think it's worth doing so yeah um so i checked if
there's a google drive integration so there is something that lets you pull the files directly from
google drive into resource space without downloading it but it looks like you have to run a cyber server
um so yeah not going to work for us especially since we don't have that set up so we're probably going
to have to do the old way of you know you just download all the files and then we just put them in and then
use an lm or just manually put in the details unfortunately and then um the second thing was i know
we talked about a like backup or automatically putting it back into google drive um so that way
we have two copies right one in resource space one in google drive if you ever need so i was trying to
check and it looks like there is no native plugin for that sorry by native plugin i mean there's no way
for you to like there's no um thing that they provide that will just instantly work out of the box
right like you just download it and then you run it and then it works there's nothing like that
we would have to probably like do it ourselves basically all right so one of the so there's
like three options technically but i don't really consider number two an option because you basically
have to go through a middleman and then most of the middleman software stuff is like paid right so
not really an option if you want to keep this low cost um yeah so realistically only two options so the
first one is you mix um apis and web hooks um to break that down an api is basically something that
gives us access to like resource-based functionalities um if we want to do it not in resource space so for
example um it will be like ways to maybe something like bulk import something into resource space without
ever opening um this tab you just pull up like a command terminal or something and then you run the like
run the script or you run the code and then it will do something with resource space basically
yeah and then a web hook is a similar idea in that um you can like just basically do it over the web and
then it'll notify resource space or it'll pull some sort of resource-based feature like uploading
yeah so in this case it would be basically when you go to resource space and you upload a file right so let's
say i upload the file of my dog right then it would basically send like um i guess you can call it a
notification right it will basically send a notification um to our custom script right um and then the the
custom script would like receive a notification they'd be like okay now that i've been notified then i know to
upload this file also to google drive right because google drive also has their own um code system that you can
pull from basically yeah so the entire thing would be like i upload my picture to resource space
resource space and the notification to the script um the script sends the notification to google drive and
then uploads it there essentially um is the first option and then the second option is um we use something
called r clone yeah so i won't go into detail but our clone basically um it's kind of like a data dump
they'll pull all the they'll pull all the files and then you can just run that on your own computer
right um so it would be a little bit more complicated since we would have to um change where resource space
stores the the files or we'd have to have like dedicated um folders for the photos but once we have the
dedicated folders um then you can basically use our code to just copy all the files and then you run it on a
schedule and it would automatically upload it back to google drive right so if we do go forward with
like the backup plan then we would we would probably already be using something like our code so we would
just have to set a schedule for it to basically upload it into google drive essentially sorry i i hope
that made sense i broke down the terminology well uh is there any questions on the google drive part
uh no question
okay uh sounds good if there's no questions from anybody else then um you can move on to the amazon
integration um i know we talked a lot about amazon and like amazon s3 um last time so i looked into that
too um so amazon s3 is essentially the same as google drive um where again there's like middleware platforms
right i don't want to do that um you can just mix in the resource space um api with the amazon s3 api or
you can do something similar with our clone where you just like schedule the file upload back into
amazon s3 yeah i have less experience with amazon s3 so i don't really know the specifics but um it
should work almost exactly the same way as google drive essentially um yeah just amazon s3 would be like
pure storage of course right so while the google drive would allow so for some like very limited
like browsing stuff s3 would just be storage only as far as i'm aware yeah um any questions on the amazon part
okay that's good um yeah and then the next part was um quad flare integration so
um this part's a little bit more important um yeah i'm not sure how aware you guys are of like
what cloud flare is and to be honest i'm not like the most advanced in cloud flare either but what cloud
flare does is it basically gives you like a url for people to access the site right so basically you
would launch it on your own local version right so and you can see um it's running on my local so the url is
like local host a local host right you can see in that url but the word cloud cloud flare would do it
is that it would give you like a new like domain name or like a url name and then just by accessing
that url people can then go into the resource space so i believe if you're since the back end is hooked up
to your local if the local does not run then people cannot access um the website which is why we were
talking about like leaving the computer on before um yeah i i feel like we have a cloud flare domain
since um i know when i go to the end of the library and i try to scrape stuff there's a cloud flare
like pop-up that appears so i feel like we have a domain name and then that way we can maybe just like
integrate it into something to do with cloud flare but um i haven't done like the most research into that
since i don't know if that's something we want to do like i think we probably need to do it to let more
people access but yeah not too sure um on that part regarding the decisions yeah um any questions on that
part
um so you know for cloud cloud uh flare um you're saying that's used to provide an url yeah so cloud
flare is basically um yeah so it would give you like uh oh wait actually all right sorry yeah sorry
uh i just thought something yeah cloud flare is basically kind of like uh i don't know web hosting
is the right word but it would let people also access it because right now i don't think you
guys can access it because this is running on my own local version right so if you guys try to put
this in it would open up your own like local house part on your own pc which wouldn't lead you anywhere
because it's not open right it's not leading anywhere so i think you would need uh kind of like a middleman
or like cloud flare or something like that to access like a broader internet and then let people
access it i believe that's the correct way okay yeah um sorry the other thought i had was that um
i might be running into the cloud flare pop-up because we use google sites right google sites might
already be running through cloud flare which is why um we have that issue yeah so in that case then um
it might be a little bit more complicated since for cloud play you need to kind of have like a domain
name basically you need to pay them for url to like use their space basically so yeah again we're running
into that like payment issue right um i i feel like we had something to do with cloud flare um up there in
the pricing uh it's yeah i don't really want to find it right now but yeah i think we had a pricing for
that but yeah basically you're just like it's almost like you're paying for like a spot i like spectrum
right you're like paying for that storefront so people can go into your store otherwise you're just
operating like out of the back of your car right it's very hard to find but if you go to spectrum
and then you pay spectrum for that store for that like domain name then people can more easily access
into that website um if that example makes sense to you guys yeah um if we feel that we're at that point
where we can have that discussion with it i think we can um so yeah you know how we have a lot of like
service dot pdc dot org right order dot pdc dot org yeah um we yeah so we can we can have something
like that but uh the other question i'm not sure how to answer as well is like the whole server situation
um yeah is is it possible for it not to run locally is there some kind of uh
uh other other options other than a local circle um i can do some more research into that too um
i believe when holly and i were looking it was either you run it locally or you run it in cloud
or you run it on the cloud on resource space's own like cloud storage thing so that would probably be
permanently online but again since you're using resource space's cloud thing then you're gonna have to pay for
that too right yeah but it is part of the resource space right like there's something that there's
some third party is that right uh it's their own resource space actually so it would it would be first
party because it's resources space's own cloud thing oh okay yeah so they already have their own
they offer their own cloud hosting kind of service that if you guys want we can like look into also
yeah uh yeah holly and i doing sorry holly oh sorry they're going so resource space
uh if you do i think if i remember correctly is if it is free for like less than 10 gigabytes i think
uh it's just for our testings because in the future it's just more and more and then
uh so the virtual machines i think they can do that that's why i was looking for azure and
uh oracle but oracle is out of stock and as there was some student free credits something
okay yeah but yeah that's why you they they ask us to like pay hundreds thousands a year for their
services because they are hosting those for us yeah because if you do it local you also need to pay something
uh don't look like research spreads it's too expensive yeah that's great i never considered it
yeah sorry so that's why like yeah how are you and i like we knew there was a cloud option but that's
why we were only looking at the local option because we wanted to like keep costs down right so we thought
it would be cheaper to just keep the pc running compared to getting a cloud server or something like
that yeah yeah so that that might be a bottleneck we need to clear um because i don't know how like the
ga can manage like a computer running yeah yeah okay okay so maybe if you feel that we're ready to have
that discussion with ip we can have yeah that's a question but we can um ask joseph first and then if
you need to bring other workers um you can or maybe they can have their own discussion but um i think if
we're ready here we can talk to at least um yeah about these kind of questions okay yeah sounds good uh for
sure we can do some more uh research but yeah that's it for the naming and then like integration parts so
like any last minute questions before we move on to holly's part not from you okay um sounds good in that
case uh holly saw you man okay i need to open up the screen share okay access
wait wait i need to reopen sorry that's okay yeah
about sharing screen one but yeah it was pretty fast to run resource space so it shouldn't be that bad
either we do need to like boot it on yeah
you can see right
yep music yeah
so i'm trying to get here like to like white the color to white the worries i haven't done that yet
but i just want to put like this kind of face here and then
so you can select like different
how many photos you want in one page and then so this is just what we mentioned like
the naming things like the derivatives like the small sizes so we already
get like you don't need to know like the actual size of each
we need to replace this with the maybe some better versions maybe and then you can do different
it's for like here you can just search different things
um
i hope it works here searching but i don't think it really works
oh it works okay perfect
i think these are just placeholder or something
yeah but when you search everything can pop up and then
um so here's filters and yeah we still need to work on this but it is the structures here
you can select like different things
and
we also need to fix this and you can see all the data here
uh
and you can uh to if you find something like not right you can just request it
admin or i think admin or reviewers we can discuss on that
uh so when you go to the review queue i think it will be here
yeah i don't know why mine is so slow
it's somewhere but not here
i was playing around late like this it was here
uh
and
yeah
i also have different collections where right now they really work but
you can see like uh we really need to go to something specific orders you can find it
and here's the upload um yeah we also need to fix that like i guess i don't think people want to put so many things
they don't want to upload this but just the required ones
and for different yeah they're just all too much worry but that's what they need to do and then we can just submit
and these are just for amy's
uh just it's here because in the exhibit but we still need to uh do like a lot of research and
trying to figure out what it what is what
yeah
yeah maybe here is someone they want to get this
approved but they don't have that like the rights or something so they can use so they will get
kind of notification or something requests so they can just approve them
they can just
it's just
everything just here but
it's a lot to do so
here um
if a lot of things you can view
but
we just need really
need more time to work on
all the details because this is what real
them should be like they have different things so you can see seven and then
you have different different things so when it search
you can just get it's just much much helpful
oh this is a metadata by like small small details and this is admin so
you can see the most things but when you're real use normal user you don't see this much
um
it's just here but we just need to take time to work on every details
so help center
it's too ai but the things are here
yeah not too much things but yeah like this works much better than last week much much more details
heli did you have to customize a lot of these
what what's the last one
did you have to customize a lot of what you just showed us like basically all the
functions under workflow um so you know like uh all the air right now they can do like long deep
search for like 10 minutes 20 minutes and they have like research reports so i just feed them to ai and
they will come out with all these like small small details but yeah you know it's very in general but we
just need more time to do everything in details so this part is just so in our style
you can press command k or control k you can get a search function so there are some websites you just
copy the prompt and just tell it get copy paste and you will come up with this uh this is from this is from
our identity.tcc.org or us something so and this is like this view or like great view or something
and this is also copy paste i just tell uh you need to have one here oh i remember i said i need one here
but i don't know why it's gone yeah i just did it um like off nowhere
so like for this screen did you have to customize like those type of things like for example that per
page that drop down did you did you customize those four numbers no yeah just decide but it's better like
it's pretty good like you have five and you can just scroll six rows
uh sorry just to clarify real quick um uh yeah it's kind of is has to be like customized a little
bit it uses the resource space like back end but since this is just a ui it's just kind of like a skin
covering and then we just uh uh how they just kind of ask the llm like how to basically like put on the
like basically asked how to put on makeup for it so back end still works with resource space these are
most of these are based like resource space functionalities they're just like integrated
and made to look like a little bit better okay i'll back with it yeah it does and then when heli says
there still needs a lot of work what is that referring to like when i click something it doesn't really work
uh-huh so somehow the function needs to be linked up right still yeah it's okay we have things here but
they only have to just outside the inside doesn't work and is uh once let's say the piles are loaded
into the back end like what what kind of work needs to happen for for it to actually work work
uh so let's say someone upload something here so what i want to do is just they can just upload maybe but
everything should be like default or something like you get a date default by accessing the metadata files
and then uh the reviewers will decide like different things
so right now if someone submits something um they can submit by by using this page and then whatever they
typed into those fields that you just show in like it's number one cat number one yeah like all those
things will get recorded into the into the um database right now like the one that we created vocal
yeah like what we want is so you just upload here and then it will get oh yeah um it will be like in
the places we want to store them and then uh but they just put on like different things like so that
uh the reviewers will know when when when where what and then if you need something specific for different use
for different places or it's only for internal or maybe it's better like print something and then uh
uh yeah reviewers will decide whether this should be on but most i think most of the time and everything
just on just make sure there's no like copyright stuff uh just make sure they take pictures by themselves
so just just just a very rough idea like how long would it take to build this so that it's functional
fully functional
i hope it's working but it really depends on ai like like they say so much like every time i just tell it
oh you need to get this down like demo down or like you need to make this like version one but like
in the end they're just running for like five hours ten hours okay and like doing nothing
uh all right it's doing in the back but i don't really see it right right because like i every time i
like before i go eat i just uh here's a task that you can run for like hours and before i go out or
one wake up or before i sleep i just run this for like 12 hours i don't really know what to do it
okay okay okay so it it it may be functioning uh but probably there's still things that need to be
either cleaned up or like yeah i mean if anything to be clean out like right now it's just very sore ai
i look at this every day so it's just very very ai
we don't really need those in actual pages i still need to view all the uh those damn youtube videos and
trying to do this and also like their search functions like they already have like ai searching
back in like seven years ago like 2019 there is much much cleaner
okay so it's more like kind of simplifying it from what you have right now
yeah around a bit of that work yeah you don't want to see this much finish
this is too hard oh and that part you asked ai to do like it's like oh simplify this part keep
only this something like that kind of like that but you need to be very very specific because
like i said you just wait for one hour and it's either not doing anything you can see or it's doing
it's making it much worse
okay i see but if sometimes like when i be very specific like this like i copy paste this
like i need all the damp uh features most important things here like so it's here but when but this
still makes no sense here because everything is here while they are all here
it's just too busy here and the colors
just need more time and hopefully i will get it done
and yeah because there are many like blockers on if i want to get it on
car or somewhere hosted for free for small batch of like internal testings
yeah i also need to go to those different websites to get them down like oracle is out of stock
right right oh i'm gonna jump ahead and ask my question um to jackie jackie currently how easy it
is it to get like the non um non-kdc specific photos like if people want photos of flowers of like ocean like
is it did there's just so many places to get those for free nowadays um yeah actually yes it's it's pretty
easy to get those okay so i'm starting to wonder for our stock media whether we should really just
narrow down to those things that we can't get outside
so like our sources just the free uh resources outside and like uh some member pictures
like for example flowers right maybe that's not something we need to put in our stock media
yeah but when someone wants something they go outside and how can i make sure this is like no copyrights
yeah jackie do they usually clarify this is like free there's no copyright you do not need to acknowledge
um yeah um if you go to like a um stock photo site for example pexels or unsplash they will say
which ones you can use freely and which ones you have to pay royalty so usually like sites like getty
you'll have to pay royalties too um and then some sites like canva
um because we have a subscription that we don't actually pay for um but we do have like a pro version
because we're a non-profit we can use those licensed images um for our our use because we have a contract
with them so anything we get from for example canva um we are we are allowed to use because we have that
active subscription and um most of those images are uploaded by users anyway so it's not like canva is
hosting them so whoever's uploading them has also um given the rights they basically signed the rights
over to canva so that canva can redistribute those to whatever whichever users and we're one of those
um and i think it's also the same for pexels and unsplash where if you have that subscription or you
have that access then you can you can freely use it so i don't think it's very i don't know how that
one church ended up using like a copyright photo it must have been like something that was not very
stock in terms of the content so maybe it was like a specific location or a specific um something that
you can really tell that it's unique to like propriety um you need to like that one company or that one
entity yeah yeah so um that's kind of how i understand it like stock stuff should be like
either our own stock things that where you can't identify who the person is in the photo like you
can't see the face you can't really tell like from the back who they are um or like it's just it's like
church property like parts of the church property things like that or um another thing i do use quite
a lot just for church content is if it's like an ordained minister an ordained creature or deacon and
we know that they're full-time workers and um they have like a really good reputation then we just go
ahead and use that photo and we actually still try not to use like their full face um just for their
privacy as well but yeah things like that did that answer yeah okay sorry if i could ask a
question real quick would it be yeah i know it's kind of like a sensitive matter but would it be
possible to like get more details of what happened with that like copyright thing because if we have
more details then maybe we can try to plan around it or see if it's like even a concern because um yeah
yeah um i don't know too much detail but the when i got looked in is basically some kind of a nature
photo i think it was like some ocean type scene and it was just on a webpage um in the indonesian site and
um so so then we got a letter from like uh like a law firm saying that oh this is uh if this is
a copyrighted image um and then so they just demand that we pay them for using that image and so
yeah so we basically negotiated we settled for a lesser amount that we ended up paying them um
but they're yeah the whole premise is it was a copyrighted image and somehow our our worker found that
somewhere online and then just use it without realizing that if they did the copyrighted image
okay sounds good and then this is like in indonesia right not not us on our indonesian site but the you
know like people always well even the indonesia site if you look at it is still a tdc.org slash id something
like that right so basically all these legal issues still normally come through to ia um and then ia will
work with whichever respective ga right to resolve the issue um if the local gav need to be brought in
right so we had to like inform the indonesia ellen like uh you know take down the photo and we have
to figure out how to deal with the whole um the issue right the payment issue yeah yeah okay i see
yeah sounds good thanks um yeah i don't know if we can really do anything around that but yeah yeah
yeah i think i think more and more gays are are more getting more experience with you know like telling
how to make sure they use only the images that are copyright free right or that it's committed um my
only question is like i should be royalty free right royalty free right yeah um and so jesse the other
quick question i have also is like are there any of these photos where they said you have to include
on the photo itself
or much are free like you can just with use them without acknowledging that's a good question um
um i do okay so off the top of my head i do know that some of them um they highly encourage giving the
credit like signing the credit of where the photo is but from what i remember that was just highly
encouraged um just as a best practice sort of thing but i don't think i remember seeing that and
honestly when i use canva i don't i don't say anything but you can see um within canva who is the owner of
that photo um usually yeah so so they may not necessarily require us to use it right to to
to include that acknowledgement no absolutely not okay okay then that's good because that that would be
um that would be more of a reason why we want to have our own you know stock photos of flowers and
whatnot right if we have to acknowledge basically all of them or a lot of them um then we might as well
but like i think for music i believe that's usually still the case right we have to acknowledge yeah for
music it's a bit more strict about that okay so that so then that that's the reason why i was thinking
earlier um for stock photos do we because we can go we can really go all out we can have hundreds of
thousands of photos right so we're really opening it to like oh we should have trees we have we should
have flowers we should have right um pencil we should have yeah we can just go all out right versus
if we can really get those free photos so easily out there do we want to only focus on the ones that
we can't find outside right let's say baptism right baptism in like in living water right like in rivers
in oceans like those kind of photos and then you know with the person's head bowing down like do we want
to focus more on those kind of photos yeah i would really like to have a lot of those photos actually
i did request to annabelle for the ui ux and the graphic design team at mvp to um consider taking
pictures i actually i gave her a list so for example a group of people praying in the chapel with lots of
negative space and things like that or you know bible study outdoors cannot see the faces with a lot
of negative space things like that so i do request those um hopefully we can start building up a larger
library of that kind of content um i so i just took a look at canva it does say like for example i
searched up a flower pink uh peony bouquet on a sky background and it does tell me um who it's just
like a username who it's by it doesn't say the name and then it does say that this is pro content and
it's included with canva terms um so oh no sorry uh included with canva teams um and that's what we have
so yeah we it says canva teams subscribers get this image for free so oh it doesn't say anything about um
usage or like acknowledgement and you don't even know who it's from and interestingly enough um this is from getty images
so this is so i guess canva has access to getty images oh interesting
and usually getty images is not free
um i had a good question um say for example a lot of the projects like pocket calendars a lot of the
pictures are taken from our own stock photo library right that's right yeah and they're usually nature
oriented yeah i'm wondering if there are other projects like that are you suggesting that um
those photos can be taken from other places like getting images or other places
images like that are you suggesting that you're using the same exact nature right yeah that's what i was
thinking too yeah
okay so there might still be a a good enough reason
to have our own at least nature images that are are regularly not regularly but at least are used for a regular context
yeah
do we okay so for the pocket calendar we almost would never use anything other than nature
nature nature
yeah i mean i could see us using like um if you're talking about um the water baptism
um those types of photos maybe we would use those um but i guess it just depends on the verse right
yeah
so far all of them is like very nature-y
all yeah yeah
yeah the i guess going back to my original suggestion i'm just wondering like how
big do we want the stock media system to be oh the bigger the more the pay
yeah
i feel like that might be one of the
potential blocker we have to do
i don't know if there's a way to limit this but um like say for example flowers we already have like
a lot of flower photos like can is it possible to
somehow limit the amount of people contributing to that particular photo
like for every nature photo two or three church photos or something yeah
yeah i don't know yeah request to the uh to annabelle
yeah because it doesn't go through admin to review right can admin just
be like oh like not review or not accept it because they're already a lot of a certain type of photo
yeah i think i think that is probably possible but it sounds like there's like two things going on so
like hailey and enoch are building the system and it sounds like we also need content managers to work
within the system so it's kind of like two different teams and we haven't really talked about the content
side yet because i think they don't really have a clear idea yet of what information to include
because we haven't like we haven't told them because i think we don't even really know ourselves we have
to make those decisions right that's like what i'm kind of getting out of it
yeah i think nobody knows i've thought through this enough um to really know the full picture um but
this is part of our discovery process right it's going through this um to see what is even possible
and then right and then now these questions pop up like we need to address these questions
um yeah to be fair if you really wanted to and if you like trust the people uploading them enough
then you can just like kind of give them like open access but holly and i were just kind of a little
iffy on open access because as you know sometimes people um may just like overlook stuff or uh just
stuff happens right so that's why we're just like thinking about requests only but if you really trust
people we can also skip the whole approval process if you really need it yeah i think um
right we did mention by default joanna would be the content approver and if she needs to involve
other people um if there's too much work i think she can build a team right but at the very least
as a project manager i guess she would be hopefully our default approver
um and it might yeah i don't know how much we can control who the contributors are um is it right is
it possible to set it up that like basically you need to have an account to be able to submit yeah yeah
uh i just try like you need to log in so you can submit like we can trace back like whoever did it is so
if you want like more you can just uh maybe we can have some specific code like access code like
uh sign up codes distributed maybe by ga usga or different churches so you just go to the council and like you can get the uh sign up uh code for that
so otherwise you cannot sign up okay you can only view and view like as a viewer and you can never be a contributor unless you get access code
uh okay that's what we did before for up like a beta yeah a beta version
yeah the files also tell you who's uploaded them so if you ask if you tell people to use their real name
or like their church and their real name then you should be able to like track down who contributed to
the photos pretty easily um joanna i think like if we only open the contribution access to the people who
are regularly right contributing like for example right chris chen or could just stand like would we give them
access um so even if they continue to load new nature photos we probably wouldn't be too concerned about them
uploading too many right yeah i don't see that there's people like regularly um contributing to
the google photos right now um but i know previously we talked about like the mvp um is it
like the graphic design team or the one of the teams they all have access to
the google library to the google photos library yeah so they would be the viewer then right they're not
necessarily contributing and then maybe at the end of every mvp workshop um the team lead can
uh only upload the photos that yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah
yeah i think it would be possible if it's just the team lead that uploads it
and i think so far that has been more or less the case right when they uploaded to the google photo
account um that the team needs to be the one to make sure i see i don't know exactly what happened
last year during mvp because i shared the um folder with annabelle but i don't know if she gave direct
access to that folder to all the team members or it was just her who did it yeah okay okay i guess
regardless at the end she could still be the person to go through and delete the photos that probably
don't need to be in there and then right and then remove access from all the participants by that point
and then um because the way it is right now is some of the ex-participant or previous
participant that continue to take a lot of good photos and want to contribute more after that mvp
then that's when we create these specific folders for them like chris uh um paulina right probably not
yeah i think it's just in the year 2021 whoever the team meet was just created individual folders for
all right but i think it probably should have been just like an mvp 2021 and it would just combine all
those into one similar to like how it's already combined into the mvp yeah
i had a question about the naming um system that we were talking about before is it very tedious to name
every photo say like the team lead has to upload 200 some photos each would they have to go in one by one
to like label everything right it's auto generated
auto generated okay
i guess like if you wanted to change parts of the name you would have to do that one by one right
like we can do like some bulk upload like you can just apply like let's say bible to these photos you
just upload the something like you can do like a whole folder or you can do like this specific ones
if you can do like select and these these photos need to add well it's much more complicated but we can try
i see oh okay like you can just create your like first you can create a folder and then you can just
bulk upload like buy different things you want to upload to this and then you add the same
elements to this this folder if photos you want to upload
i see sorry just to add on real quick um since the photographers also will need to put the
photos onto their computer first before they can upload to resource space
um if you really need to we could also try providing like some sort of custom script to make
like automating that easier right so for example it would be like oh like what do you want to name
this group of photos right and then like oh how many images do you want to upload right and it would
just sequentially go through them and then you can just name them something generic for example right
so you can just that way you can just say oh you know date is going to be this and then um some sort
of topic here right and then sequential and then you just just mass bulk um rename them there should be
like features for that just natively built into the computers i think that would be helpful
yeah yeah so if that's like a real concern then we can look into that in the future as well
and then just on resource space is it possible to like on the um home page is it possible to search up
by contributor like say a contributor wants to okay
um i think i read somewhere that professional stock photographers spend um up to half of their work
time tagging and sorting and keywording so that it is a big part of it
uh jackie the two things that you just shared the first one is it just to show us that we can get
like these kind of photos pretty easily yes i just wanted to uh share what it kind of looks like
from pexels it does say it's free to use oh okay and then for canva because we have access to um
um we have access to i guess they're non-free photos those were the terms so basically uh it does say in
the terms that we have access to it in perpetuate forever perpetuity perpetuity
yeah so if they do swap it out with something else or they take it off we still once we have taken
like use that photo we can use it forever um just there's some limits like we don't want to we can't
use it uh within the logo like there's just no okay like for our uses um i don't think we would encounter
that right like social media posts and pocket calendars right right yeah yeah and they say like you can't
um like just use the image without um modify without like putting something on top of it or like
you can't like print it and sell it as your own artwork right right okay
um i'll wait if you let me share my screen i can show the uh check which contributor
uh yeah so um yeah i didn't do that extensively as holly did so everything's contributed by admin user
which is me so if you go to so sorry so again base resource space right the search box on the right
and you go to advanced search you go all the way down and you search for who contributed like just
type in admin that user will pop up right yeah so you can check by which contributors there are you
just need to set up the contributors of course yeah sorry just answer the question about the contributors
um you also had a question about howie's version um for i think it was one of the pages with the tabs
one through five on the fourth step it was like usage scope um and there are different options does that change
how the photos are categorized or organized um if you click a certain one or what's the purpose of that
like do you mean this like upload here yeah the usage scope um number four
uh
like you can just i mean these are ai but there is a reason why they're here maybe so um
so like you can just be more specific on this maybe like when you go to the filter on the library
and you want to do like uh print you select print or these print like tags they just come up
so it doesn't change like the way that the photos are organized at all no like this is just actress
i see yeah i still need to watch more other good videos on this okay
so um
do you know how did you come up with your version is it just you didn't use a link to build it you just
like pull whatever it is uh it's a like ready version
yeah sorry my version is how it looks like straight out of the box so if everybody just goes to the
resource space and then like follows instructions and it gets running a computer it will look like mine
essentially yeah yeah so that's why like that i think the budget is almost like no customization at
all it's basically like it works pretty well out of the blocks to be honest yeah
okay i don't know
if we if we want to write um implement this we have to we have to be able to manage it right
for the next 20 years
so let's see how do we do that let me ask
all right thank you like a little bit more specific on what you mean by manage like is there any specific
aspect um right to bring up yeah like that's a company like ultimately add
need like additional i'm sorry add additional
fields like data yeah yeah that's that's pretty easy um
yeah it will be much better maybe like right now i do it for a month maybe i can just do it one one one
day it's only gonna be more powerful like you can just talk what you want they will just
do everything and they will look like this much better
and this is even for like six years ago
yeah and then uh base resource space if you want to add more fields it's also pretty easy
um you can just go into the menus and it has yeah it's it's like built-in feature to add more fields
and then uh determine if it's going to be like necessary and what like what you want the field to
specifically be yeah
um
yeah yeah so if you guys want to like come up with some more questions too um for holly and i then maybe
we can try to answer them and then maybe that can help refine what our true like purpose will be like
going forward we can narrow it down to search a little if you guys want
yeah do you know what do you think um i think ultimately like we probably will still be there
right with still be the project manager um and maybe you can comment on that
um i just think the bottom line is if it's user friendly for everyone because not everyone is super
tech savvy um so i feel like as long as contributors can easily um contribute to this and um do it some
like um like um on their own accord i think that would be the most important and then also um like
how it's organized like the tags the naming system everything that's easy to find um i think that's also
important too
yeah that's why i like i spend time on this like i just want to make it much easier right now the the
the one i'm doing is uh i would say it's very like the layout is not good enough not like very
user friendly or like because we all we want just some people just upload and let's call it a day that's
it and they want to find something that's the most important things that's why i want to see resource
space no this is so hard
yeah i think either way we're also gonna have to create like a walkthrough of any story
clear especially if they have like naming conventions or anything we're probably already gonna have to
make a walkthrough so we can probably just add that just want to make everything easy
yeah i think what would be helpful is maybe like coming up with like an inch page of instructions
of how to upload and like a naming system um that might be helpful yeah like i'll just make it as easy
as like you use google photos google drives you just upload everything and right yeah you can just
search up things that's the ultimate goal i think for most of people like we can be more much much work
but the users just make it easy easy easy
yeah in terms of like the maintenance side i'm not sure if that would be
um for you guys to maintain or yeah oh um it's just about price maybe like yeah i can do it maybe
let's see if it's in the future
yeah that's why we made some of the choices we did so we don't have like tech that in the field
sorry tech that is basically like just choosing something that works now instead of planning ahead
right like we're also trying to like plan ahead that's why we're like thinking about like vocal hosting
um
um jackie do you have any recommendation on where to go from here yeah actually i was thinking about that
um i was so wondering do you think it's time to also involve anabella too um because she's uh pretty
active in the in the i guess like the content of this project um i'm wondering if we can
remember how we were talking about doing like a limited version like just using the previous year's mvp
um to test it was that what um the photos were already limited to in the presentation of the
um you know the demo from today were those the photos only from mvp 2020 something six five 2025.
yeah we did talk about using is it mvp 24 right oh 24 okay
um so like for that those content i think what's kind of missing possibly is like um like the information
of the of those photos are not in the they're not in the um the mock-up that um hailey and enoch built
so we can't really tell what's going on and also they don't really know what to name it so i think
that information might need to come from the content managing side um but if we can just limit it to
however photos those were i don't remember if it was like 200 or 50. um that might be a good way to
test it to see like how user friendly it is without taking up a lot of people's time i'm wondering
because i think ultimately one of the goals was to categorize the photos um but that may not have been
possible with this intern group because they don't really know what the content might be that would
have had to come from the content manager side which would happen and i don't know that that's what
i'm thinking it's not like fully formed but i don't know if anybody can expand on that
um yeah so joanna and nfl are in that same project and managers group um the i think nfl's role so far
has been um actually apart from the project managers and that she was a team lead for the graphic graphic
design and user experience design um team it's just that usually that team produces a lot of the stock photos
that get fed into the overall stock basically the stock media library that joanna is the project
that's right because like pastor sam also contributes to right yeah and some other non-mvp participants
of the past like you know chris chen jerry kong like those people who are very into taking photographs
um um they have been they have at least had one point to do quite a number of colors
yeah so i think yeah maybe we could um i don't know if somehow okay if we don't want to involve
animal yet if somehow joanna is able to like use their product somehow i'm not sure how
we could do that um and then like give her feedback on whether this is the route we can go because i i'm
not the i'm not the one who will make the decision so i'm not exactly sure what we want
yeah yeah it's sorry yeah go ahead i was just wondering is there something that i could try out this
like uploading a photo or like uploading the past photos
yeah that's one of the things we're talking about because right now um yeah so as you can see my
version is completely different from holly's version right and that's because we're both running on our
local own separate versions right so that's one of the issues we're talking about where we might
probably need something like that cloudflare domain so everybody can connect to it something like that
using like a url type of thing yeah yeah like a centralized source because otherwise it's all
local and you guys can't touch any of that right yeah oh i'm sorry and then yeah then holly and i
didn't want to centralize too fast because again that way if we just need to abandon the project there's
no harm done basically is there um are we at a point yet to decide on one of the um platforms um so
either holly's or enoch so that you can work together
sorry to be clear um yeah holly's version just builds on the original base version my version is
not really my version it's literally just the standard default like i haven't done any customization work
to it holly's is just like uh that way so if you want to think of it like my face my version is
basically just my face right but holly's version is kind of like the makeup on the face it just builds
on it essentially so it's like the same thing oh okay all right so you are you are working on the
same thing uh well technically holly's doing most of the work on that side to be real because again
like it's a local version right so i can't touch the work he does basically that's right yeah is what
you're doing huge enough where it cannot be done like on a free um i don't know like a free post like
you know some some of them they have like trial posting i don't know um i don't know very much about
web hosting oh i if you want i maybe can do it like on answer but more ideally it's oracle but same thing so
if you want to play around i mean i can get it down like you can play around with it but
yeah like when it's scope is big enough or like let's get a bit to you like in the future you just
need to make it somewhere else but right now yeah that's what i'm trying to do i i i just want to get
it uh everyone can just trying to upload things but every time yeah i just say okay it's done
i just tell you to review and just come keep coming going back and something i have to fix all the
things and i just have to wait and just pointing out another bug and it has to figure it fix again
but yeah if you want we can get it somewhere on like you i put in a chat like it's a website but i think it's
older one oh no oh yeah okay can you um can you i'm gonna paste this into our google chat meeting i don't
[REDACTED credential discussion] so this was like pretty old maybe last
i don't know if you want to do it but i don't know if you want to do it but i can update this so
the [REDACTED-CREDENTIAL-LIKE-TEXT] is for uh i mean i do not remember other credential-like values oh okay so joanna can
use this to try it out uh no this is just a shell oh that's what i was trying to figure out like
hosting somewhere else so like azure virtual machine so we can really link both things together and yeah
okay i'm gonna say something that i don't think anybody wants to hear but it kind of sounds like
like there is a high possibility that there's going to be a lot of maintenance required on this um
project that people who do not have a cs background really cannot do so like um
heli what you're doing with giving ai the tasks to do um without this kind of background like you
have it like if someone hasn't gone through the steps and learned about dam and all of that like
how you and enoch have been learning about it um the past few weeks they will not be able to um maintain
the bugs and things like that because i know that for joseph his full-time job is basically debugging
or something like that so i'm i think i'm suspecting that it may be too complicated that is
sorry uh yeah just as quick uh clarification uh do you mean like ai in terms of like for the photos and
stuff because um the i just speeds it up like you don't have to use the air at all if you're not
contributing that many photos if you contribute say like 50 you can just upload like like 10 at a time
for example and you can manually go through and then like add the tags yourself so on the user side when
it's all done like there shouldn't be that many issues the flow should be pretty good right like you
just like rename the photo or you rename the file on your own computer and then you upload it and then
you just like select all the tags and then you should like be pretty good there's like maybe one or two
more steps beyond that but it shouldn't be like super complicated on the user end it's just a little
bit more complicated for us because we're working like the back end like maintenance and then setting
up kind of end so yeah hopefully the end goal shouldn't be like that bad sorry just does that clarify
anything or oh yeah yeah absolutely yeah yeah i was actually concerned about no i think the way that you
set it up for the user is pretty brilliant it's like very all-encompassing and um i think the way that
you do it is very thorough and i i'm just concerned about the back end maintenance part because once you
set it up something might fail eventually and like if yeah that's just what i'm concerned about but of
course like yeah please prove me wrong that would be great um but it's yeah so how how can we get to
a point where joanna can try out um like with a limited number of photos to for her to manage and
she can let us know yeah i would try that and when i get it done i will just share it and okay chat
is that going to be a lot of work i'll just ask ai to just click something click click click and i just
build a review and okay continue okay create okay yeah it's just ai using your uh safari chrome and
in the end you just click that payment ish thing
what payment ish no no no no not payment because we got like azure student credits or
they're small enough like we don't need to pay just like ai will keep the last one for you to like
confirm sorry you mean a lot of work to set up or a lot of work for joanna to add the photos
because there are two different things no the the to set up the thing for joanna to use not sure it's
just a few like platforms oh okay that's what i think we might do is that okay yeah that's what i
was trying to do last week that's why i bring this because i was trying to use oric of it didn't work
oh okay okay yeah i definitely learned a lot like from this whole project and so it was like whoa all
this information it's really cool yeah um yeah i don't i don't have anything else um if that's okay
for the for the plan if everyone is okay with that we can set that up okay yeah
okay so we'll wait for a text or a message from holly and enoch and then um joanna will take a look
at that and then after that joanna let us know so do we want to set a follow-up meeting or yeah we
probably should um sorry what did you say oh yeah go ahead yeah we can uh okay so what would we want
to do a week from now and then also i forget um holly and enoch when is your last day as intern for the
internship workshop oh the workshop right okay so the the week of the sixth and seventh it would be like
the last week right um would the would next tuesday be too early for a follow-up oh no no no no no no
no okay so that depends on joanna too would you have enough time like if they give you the link by i
don't know like friday or so would that be enough time for you to work um take a look over it over the
weekend um this weekend yeah oh it's father's day this weekend yeah
it'll be as easy as you just upload some photos and yeah like you do uh like google drive
yeah it should be fine i i might not be available saturday sunday but i could do
do it monday or whatever you send it okay okay yeah then um yeah maybe we can aim for next week at the
same time um sorry
oh never mind okay uh
uh sorry i can't see my full screen because the google meeting is in the way um okay i'm looking at
today and this week okay so what month uh would
uh would like 11 o'clock or 11 30 be okay on tuesday
yeah 11 to 12
oh 11 to 12 okay yeah okay great yeah looks like everyone is okay with that so we'll schedule it for
next week at 11. um okay yeah i'm pretty excited to hear what joanna has to say next week
uh thank god it it's really really impressive like what you're able to get ai to do and also kind of
like satisfying to hear that ai doesn't work all that well sometimes but um but yeah it's very impressive
um i've learned a lot so thank god um that we could be part of this discovery process and kind of like
figure out what we need to know what we don't know yet um yeah and i think we can conclude here
okay thank god all right uh see you all next week at u11 then
okay
you